

# EDWINA BADDOO

# **PERSONAL SUMMARY**

AN ENTHUSIASTIC SALES AND BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT EXECUTIVE WITH 3 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE IN THE HOSPITALITY INDUSTRY, GAINING VALUABLE SKILLS IN RELATIONSHIP BUILDING, STRATEGIC PLANNING, MARKETING, AND PROJECT MANAGEMENT. STRONG TRACK RECORD OF OUICKLY LEARNING AND ADAPTING TO NEW AND COMPLEX SITUATIONS. EAGER TO LEVERAGE A DIVERSE RANGE OF TALENTS IN AN ENGAGING PROFESSIONAL SETTING. COMMITTED TO LIFELONG LEARNING, PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT, AND CREATING, DEVELOPING, AND MAINTAINING POSITIVE CUSTOMER SERVICE AND EXPERIENCES TO INCREASE SALES THROUGH CREATIVE COMMUNICATION, FLEXIBLE, HAVE GOOD ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS AS WELL AS GREAT INTERPERSONAL SKILLS..

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- CREATIVE PROBLEM SOLVING
- FLEXIBILITY IN SITUATIONS
- GUEST SERVICE-ORIENTED
- TECHNOLOGICAL SAVVY (MS OFFICE, EZEE HOTEL SOFTWARE E.T.C)
- Self-motivated and driven by targets
- Positive Mindset

# **CONTACT INFORMATION:**

TELEPHONE: +233243078576

EMAIL:

EDWINA.BADDOO@CESARRITZCOLLEGES.CH

LINKEDIN: LINKEDIN.COM/IN/EDWINA-BADDOO



# **EDUCATIONAL HISTORY**

#### CESAR RITZ COLLEGES AND DERBY UNIVERSITY

MA in International Business in Hotel & Tourism Management

July 2017 - April 2019

ENGLISCH GRUSS-STRASSE 43, CH-3902 BRIG, SWITZERLAND

## **EUROPEAN SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS**

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE HOSPITALITY MANAGEMENT

APRIL 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

4 MANDEVILLE PL, MARYLEBONE, LONDON W1U 2BG, UK

#### ASHESI UNIVERSITY

BSC MANAGEMENT INFORMATIONS SYSTEMS

BEREKUSO, GREATER ACCRA, GHANA

AUGUST 2013 - JUNE 2016



## **CAREER HISTORY**

#### PEDUEASE VALLEY RESORT

JNR. BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

November 2020 - September 2021

- PREPARED SALES-RELATED DOCUMENTS AND PRESENTATIONS WHICH INCLUDED REPORTS
  PROPOSALS, CONTRACTS, BANQUET EVENT ORDERS, COMPETITOR ANALYSIS AND INTERNATIONAL
  AND LOCAL MARKET TRENDS.
- EFFECTIVELY DEVELOPED CONTENT TO PROMOTE AND INCREASE AWARENESS OF THE P.V.R BRAND
  IMAGE BOTH INTERNALLY AND EXTERNALLY. GATHERED MATERIALS AND ASSEMBLED INFORMATION
  PACKAGES SUCH AS BROCHURES, POSTERS AND OTHER PROMOTIONAL MATERIALS.
- SUCCESSFULLY PLANNED AND EXECUTED 12 IN-HOUSE PROGRAMMED EVENTS WHICH INCLUDED
  EVENTS FOR CHRISTMAS AND NEW YEAR ACTIVITIES. VALENTINE'S DAY EVENT, EASTER ACTIVITIES
- PROFITABLY DEVELOPED, PRICED AND SUCCESSFULLY IMPLEMENTED 6 PRODUCTS AND PACKAGES
  SUCH BIRTHDAY AND ANNIVERSARY PACKAGES WHICH CAN BE SOLD TO GUEST AS A CHANNEL TO
  GAIN REVENUE.
- SUCCESSFULLY ESTABLISHED, RETAINED AND EXPANDED PARTNERSHIPS WITH KEY MEDIA
  INSTITUTIONS AND VENDORS IN GHANA AND NEGOTIATED 5 COMPLEX CONTRACTS WITH NEW
  CLIENTS AND CLOSED 3 SHORT-TERM AGREEMENTS TO INCREASE SALES

# **CULLASAIA PRIVATE CLUB**

FRONT OF HOUSE INTERN

APRIL 2018 - NOVEMBER 2018

- EXCEEDED EXPECTATIONS IN EXCELLENT WAIT SERVICE TO ENSURE SATISFACTION
- PROVIDED EXEMPLARY SERVICE WHICH INCREASED THE CLUB USAGE.
- REWARDED FOR DEMONSTRATING IMPECCABLE MULTITASKING SKILLS IN THE BUSIEST PERIODS OF THE RESTAURANT.
- RESOLVED INTERNAL CONFLICTS BETWEEN WAITERS, THEREBY SETTING AN
   EXAMPLE FOR EMPLOYEE RELATIONS.
- SET-UP AND MANAGEMENT OF BRUNCH SERVICES AND EVENTS COORDINATION

## RELAIS & CHATEAUX IL BOTTACCIO LUXURY HOTEL

CROSS DEPARTMENTAL INTERN

AUGUST 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

- SIMPLE KITCHEN TASKS: PEELING, STORING, CLEANING, PREPARING MEALS
- LEARNING AND PRESENTING ARTS OF DISH PRESENTATION.
- Managing and controlling Housekeeping and kitchen Inventory.
- SUPERVISING AND ASSISTING IN HOUSEKEEPING DUTIES
- SUPERVISING AND HELPING WITH FRONT OFFICE DUTIES SUCH AS
  WELCOMING AND ASSISTING GUESTS IN CHECK-IN AND CHECK-OUT.
- Polishing and setting up restaurant and event spaces



# LANGUAGE SKILLS

- -ENGLISH (MOTHER TONGUE)
- FRENCH (BASIC)